

30 Ascent st Upper Keдron QLD 4055

Mob 0437 391239 Home Email bigler1@virginbroadband.com.au

PROFILE

I am 45 years old and have been in the health and fitness industry for over 20 years. In that time I have been employed with the Australian Defense Force as a medic for 8 years. I have a passion for teaching people so they can better themselves improve there quality of life.

EXPERIENCE

Medic Australian Defense Force Army

2005-2013

Operational experience East Timor eight months instructed the East Timorese army on first aide training and medical assistance with med caps and medical evacuation AME and road.

Operational experience Afghanistan six months providing emergency life saving treatment to Australian soldiers, Afghan soldiers and Afghan population delivered first aide training to Afghan national security forces.

I was employed as the Company medic at patrol base Hadrian.

Physical Therapist Kempo-Sports

1991-2005

My role was to implement and train people from work related injuries (workers compensation). Running self-defence courses for high school students.

Personal and group training in fitness, self-defense.

Infantry 5/7 RAR Australian Defense Force Army

1985-1989

Four years Infantry experience and Platoon physical trainer.

EDUCATION

Diploma's

Sports Medicine Remedial Massage Paramedical Science (Ambulance) Sports Psychology

Certificates

Air Medical Evacuation
4th Degree Black Belt Kempo
3rd Degree Black Belt in Jujitsu
Cert IV in fitness
Nutrition
Exercise rehabilitation
Weight loss
Enrolled Nurse (Division2) with general registration
Level 1 Strength and Conditioning coach
Resistance training rehabilitation
Level 2 coach
Army Physical Training cse 1988
World Muay Thai Council Referee and Judge

MILITARY AWARDS

Joint Task Force 631 Commendation outstanding Achievement East Timor

Joint Task Force 633 Bronze Commendation Afghanistan

Best at Physical Training 2005